## **RICH BOZEK**

## **FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

# RBOZEK@GMAIL.COM | LINKEDIN | PORTFOLIO

I'm a passionate and detail-oriented autodidact focused on full-stack web development and design. I have 15+ years of creative collaborations in audio and video production, design, photography, education, and artist/tour management. I take pride in my reputation for reliability, adaptability, and problem solving.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, Node.js, Python, SQL, HTML5, CSS, JSON, YAML Libraries and Frameworks: React.js, Express.js, Django, Passport.js, EJS

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB

**Other:** Git, JWT Auth, Google OAuth, JSON API, Postman, AWS, Neon, Docker, Nodemon, NPM, OOP, RESTful Routing, GitHub team workflow / version control

Miscellaneous Software: Visual Code Studio, Pro Tools certified, Final Cut Pro X, GIMP, Sibelius,

OpenOffice

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

HomeWrangler - <u>GitHub</u> | <u>App</u> - React, Express, MongoDB, Node, JWT Auth, JavaScript, CSS, HTML5 Created to lessen mental strain from repetitive household shopping and repairs.

- MERN-stack CRUD application with JWT authentication and authorization
- Acted as team leader for development group managed version control, schedule/deadlines, and team morale building
- Created with mobile-first approach and clean aesthetic to prioritize functionality for users

Reps - <u>GitHub</u> | <u>App</u> - Python, Django, Django Auth, PostgreSQL, AWS, Docker, JavaScript, CSS, HTML5 Designed to help people develop new skills through discipline and tracking practice routines.

- Python-based CRUD application using Django authentication and authorization, and AWS API
- Desktop and mobile responsive
- Streamlined interface and flexible data entry for ease of use across variety of users' goals

Shelver - <u>GitHub</u> | <u>App</u> - Node, Express, MongoDB, Google OAuth, Docker, JavaScript, CSS, HTML5 An app for music lovers to keep track of a personal music collection.

- MEN-stack CRUD application with Google OAuth authentication and authorization
- Desktop and mobile responsive, with design reflecting record-collector aesthetics

Be a Great Human: The Quizzening - GitHub | App - JavaScript, CSS, HTML5

Lighthearted quiz about being a mindful and aware human on Planet Earth.

Designed for stability armed only with my trusty JavaScript, CSS, and HTML5

#### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

## Musician / Producer, Independent Contractor, 2008 to present

- Worked in diverse areas of the music industry studio and live performance, web and graphic design, social media, engineering, composition
- Managed all elements of independent musical projects pre- and post-production, budgeting, scheduling, marketing, management, booking
- Toured regionally and nationally performed in venues such as Webster Hall (New York City), The Fillmore (San Francisco), The Metro (Chicago) – managed crew and equipment, scheduling, tour management
- Self-taught fundamental web coding languages to build and maintain artist websites

 Music education/instruction – tasks include creating curriculum for a wide range of ages, tracking lesson plans, scheduling

# Senior Photographer, Digital Homes Photography, 2015 to 2019,

 Collaborated with luxury real-estate brokers in the New York City area (including Sotheby's, Keller Williams, Coldwell Banker) to coordinate entire process of photoshoot, from planning to execution through post-production and product delivery

#### **EDUCATION**

## General Assembly, Software Engineer Immersive, December 2023 - March 2024

Completed 400+ hour immersive full-stack software engineering program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

## State University of New York at Oneonta, Music, September 2004 - May 2008

Received Academic Achievement Award, and Hewitt Pantaleoni Scholarship. Also a Member of the National Honors Society.